A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Publications (Non-Grant Related), Accession 2017:050 FA1304
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Publications, 1
  - Job #95-03: Summer/Fall Report 1995 Polling, 1994-1995 (Box 33, Folder 381)
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Texas (2 copies), 1969 June (Box 33, Folder 382)
    A report on Ford Foundation grants to organizations and institutions in the state of Texas from 1950 to April 30, 1969
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Utah (2 copies), 1964 January (Box 33, Folder 383)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Utah from 1950 to October 31, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Virginia, 1965 June (Box 33, Folder 384)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Virginia from 1950 to April 15, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Washington (2 copies), 1965 June (Box 33, Folder 385)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Washington from 1950 to April 30, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Iowa (2 copies), 1964 May (Box 33, Folder 386)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Iowa from 1950 to March 31, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Kansas (2 copies), 1964 September (Box 33, Folder 387)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Kansas from 1950 to August 15, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Kentucky (2 copies), 1963 June (Box 33, Folder 388)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Kentucky from 1942 to April 30, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Maine (2 copies), 1964 May (Box 33, Folder 389)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Maine from 1941 - March 31, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Massachusetts (2 copies), 1964 September (Box 33, Folder 390)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Massachusetts from 1946 to July 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Michigan (2 copies), 1963 May (Box 33, Folder 391)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Michigan
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Minnesota (2 copies), 1963 September (Box 33, Folder 392)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Minnesota from 1950 to August 31, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Missouri, 1964 October (Box 33, Folder 393)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Missouri from 1950 to August 31, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Montana and Wyoming (2 copies), 1965 June (Box 34, Folder 394)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the states of Montana and Wyoming from 1950 to April 30, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Nebraska (2 copies), 1964 May (Box 34, Folder 395)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Nebraska from 1943 to March 31, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in New Hampshire and Vermont, 1964 June (Box 34, Folder 396)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the states of New Hampshire and Vermont from 1950 to April 30, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in New Jersey, 1965 March (Box 34, Folder 397)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of New Jersey from 1939 to January 31, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in New York (2 copies), 1963 September (Box 31, Folder 398)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of New York from 1937 to May 31, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in North Carolina (2 copies), 1964 May (Box 34, Folder 399)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of North Carolina from 1941 to March 31, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Ohio (2 copies), 1965 May (Box 34, Folder 400)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Ohio from 1942 to March 15, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Oklahoma, 1964 October (Box 34, Folder 401)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Oklahoma from 1950 to August 31, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Oregon (2 copies), 1963 June (Box 34, Folder 402)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Oregeon from 1950 to April 30, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Pennsylvania (2 copies), 1965 April (Box 34, Folder 403)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the State of Pennsylvania from 1950 to February 15, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Rhode Island (2 copies), 1964 June (Box 34, Folder 404)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the State of Rhode Island from 1950 to April 30, 1964
  - Ford Foundation Grants in South Carolina (2 copies), 1965 May (Box 34, Folder 405)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the State of South Carolina from 1950 through March 31, 1965
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Tennessee (2 copies), 1963 May (Box 34, Folder 406)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of Tennessee from 1950 to March 15, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Texas (2 copies), 1963 May (Box 34, Folder 407)
    A report on grant to organizations, institutions, and individuals from 1950 to March 15, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in California (2 copies), 1964 April (Box 34, Folder 408)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of California from 1950 to December 31, 1963
  - Ford Foundation Grants in West Virginia, 1965 June (Box 34, Folder 409)
    A report on grants to organizations, institutions, and individuals in the state of West Virginia from 1950 to March 31, 1965
  - The Ford Foundation and the States of Kentucky and Tennessee, 1957 (Box 34, Folder 410)
    A report of grants to organizations and individuals in Kentucky and Tennessee from 1936 to September 30, 1957
  - Public Broadcasting: Progress and Promise, McGeorge Bundy, A Ford Foundation Reprint (2 copies), 1968 November 20 (Box 34, Folder 411)
    Address to the National Association of Educational Broadcasters in Washington, D.C.
  - Toward Greatness in Higher Education: A First Report on the Ford Foundation Special Program in Education (2 copies), 1964 December (Box 34, Folder 412)
  - A Ford Foundation Reprint: Public Education and Manpower Development, Marvin J. Feldman (2 copies), 1967 June 27 (Box 34, Folder 413)
    Adapted from a talk given at the Conference on Curriculum and Teaching in Depressed Areas at Columbia University
  - A Ford Foundation Reprint: Can World Famine Be Prevented?, David E. Bell (2 copies), 1968 April 2 (Box 34, Folder 414)
    Address delivered before the World Affairs Council of Inland Southern California
  - The Ford Foundation's Role in Engineering Education, Carl W. Borgmann (2 copies), 1964 February 6-7 (Box 34, Folder 415)
    Address at the American Society for Engineering Education Sixteenth Annual College-Industry Conference in Seattle, Washington
  - Beyond Family Planning, Lyle Saunders, A Ford Foundation Reprint (2 copies), 1970 March 16-17 (Box 34, Folder 416)
    Address prepared for the Second Annual Seminar on General Consequences of Population Growth, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
  - Economic Problems of Population Growth, Oscar Harkavy (2 copies), 1964 October 23 (Box 34, Folder 417)
    Paper delivered to the thirty-seventh Annual Conference of the Catholic Association for International Peace and Georgetown University in Washington, DC
  - The Upsidedown Curriculum, Junius Eddy, A Ford Foundation Reprint from Cultural Affairs (2 copies), 1970 (Box 34, Folder 418)
  - Design for Pakistan, A Report on Assistance to the Pakistan Planning Commission by the Ford Foundation and Harvard University (2 copies), 1965 February (Box 35, Folder 419)
  - The New Teacher: A Report on Ford Foundation Assistance for New Patterns in the Education of Teachers (2 copies), 1962 November (Box 35, Folder 420)
  - The Role of the Foundations in Non-Western Studies, George M. Beckmann (2 copies), 1964 November (Box 35, Folder 421)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from The Annals, Vol. 356, November 1964
  - The Ford Foundation in the 1960s: Statements of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations (2 copies), 1962 July (Box 35, Folder 422)
    paperback
  - An American Foundation and Technical Assistance, Harvey P. Hall (2 copies), 1963 (Box 35, Folder 423)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Union College Symposium, Vol. 2, No. 3, Summer, 1963
  - Music and the Ford Foundation, W. McNeil Lowry (2 copies), 1961 April (Box 35, Folder 424)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Music Journal, Vol. XIX, No. 4, April, 1961
  - The University and the Creative Arts, W. McNeil Lowry (2 copies), 1962 May (Box 35, Folder 425)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Educational Theatre Journal, Vol. XIV, No. 2, May, 1962
  - The Ford Foundation and the States of Arkansas, Kansas, Missouri, and Oklahoma (2 copies), 1959 August (Box 35, Folder 426)
    A report of grants to organizations and individuals from 1936 to March 31, 1959
  - Ford Foundation 1971 Upper Division Scholarship Competition: Directory of Awards and Honorable Mention Citations (2 copies) (Box 35, Folder 427)
  - New Report Card on the Business School, Robert Sheehan (2 copies), 1964 December (Box 35, Folder 428)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Fortune, Vol. LXX, No. 6, December 1964
  - Social Progress and the Liberal Arts College, F. Champion Ward, Ford Foundation Reprint (2 copies), 1970 June 1 (Box 35, Folder 429)
    Address delivered at the 121st Commencement of Southwestern at Memphis
  - The Ford Foundation and the Theatre, W. McNeil Lowry (2 copies), 1961 May (Box 35, Folder 430)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Equity Magazine, Vol. XLVI, No. 5, May, 1961
  - Roots of Change: The Ford Foundation in India (2 copies), 1961 November (Box 35, Folder 431)
  - The Ford Foundation in the 1960s: Statements of the Board of Trustees on Policies, Programs, and Operations, 1962 July (Box 35, Folder 432)
    Hardcover
  - Family Planning Research and Evaluation, Lyle Saunders (2 copies), 1965 (Box 35, Folder 433)
  - Foundations, Schools, and the Public Good, Edward J. Meade, Jr. (2 copies), 1965 July 14 (Box 35, Folder 434)
    Adapted from an address at the Annual School Administrators Conference, Pennsylvania State University
  - Man's Uses of Science: Some Deferred Costs, Carl W. Borgmann (2 copies), 1965 August 26 (Box 35, Folder 435)
    Excerpted from the summer commencement address, University of Tennessee, Knoxville
  - Art and Intensity, W. McNeil Lowry (2 copies), 1965 July 30 (Box 35, Folder 436)
    Address delivered at the Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies in Aspen, Colorado
  - Improving Science Education in Turkey, Eugene P. Northrop (2 copies), 1965 February (Box 35, Folder 437)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Yeni Ortaogretim (New Secondary Education), Turkey, No. 5, February 1965
  - Cross Section (2 copies), 1965 November (Box 35, Folder 438)
    Discusses education in Pittsburgh
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Vocational Education (2 copies), 1967 July (Box 35, Folder 439)
  - Careers in Teaching Engineering: A Report on the Ford Foundation Forgivable-Loan Program (2 copies), 1965 August (Box 35, Folder 440)
  - Context the World (2 copies), 1966 March 1 (Box 36, Folder 441)
    Discusses the Foreign Area Fellowship Program
  - Government as Colleague and Petitioner, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1967 May 19 (Box 36, Folder 442)
    Address delivered at the Eighteenth Annual Conference of the Council on Foundations in Boston
  - The Corrosiveness of Prejudice, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1968 February 18 (Box 36, Folder 443)
    From the President's Review in the Foundation's 1967 Annual Report
  - A Ford Foundation Reprint: Educating Administrators for Education, Charles E. Brown (2 copies), 1967 November 14 (Box 36, Folder 444)
    Excerpts from his address to the Annual Meeting of the Council of Chief State School Officers of the United States, San Juan, Puerto Rico
  - Alternatives for Urban School Reform, Mario D. Fantini (2 copies), 1968 (Box 36, Folder 445)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from the Harvard Educational Review/Volume Thurty-eight, Number One, Winter 1968
  - Minority Contractor Bonding Program: A Manual of Organizational Steps and Procedures, Prepared by the Division of National Affairs, Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1968 June (Box 36, Folder 446)
  - Technology and Cities: A Foundation Viewpoint, William C. Pendleton (2 copies), 1968 May 9 (Box 36, Folder 447)
    Address delivered before the Conference on Impending Technology - Its Challenge to Livable Cities held at the Georgia Institute of Technology in Atlanta, Georgia
  - Ford Foundation Faculty Residencies in Engineering Practice (2 copies), 1966 April (Box 36, Folder 448)
  - Skills, Scholarship and the Public Service (2 copies), 1966 April (Box 36, Folder 449)
  - The Dual Purpose Revolution, Frank Bowles (2 copies), 1966 March 14 (Box 36, Folder 450)
    Speech given at the twenty-first Annual Conference on Higher Education sponsored by the Association for Higher Education in Chicago
  - Technical Education in the Developing Countries, K. N. Rao (2 copies), 1965 December 10 (Box 36, Folder 451)
    Speech delivered to the forty-ninth Annual Convention of the Vocational Association in Miami Beach, Florida
  - American Foundations and U.S. Public Diplomacy, Francis X. Sutton (2 copies), 1968 July 22 (Box 36, Folder 452)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered before the Symposium on Future of US Public Diplomacy, Sub-Committee on International Organizations and Movements, House Committee on Foreign Affairs
  - A Decent Place to Live, Robert E. Tolles (2 copies), 1971 September (Box 36, Folder 453)
  - Housing and Urban Development: The Private Foundation's Role, Louis Winnick (2 copies), 1965 May 21 (Box 36, Folder 454)
    Address delivered at the Sixteenth Annual Conference on the Council on Foundations in Pittsburgh
  - Early School Admission Project, Edgar L. Jones (2 copies), 1965 (Box 36, Folder 455)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Southern Education Report, Vol. 1, No. 1, July-August 1965
  - Two African Patterns (2 copies), 1966 April (Box 36, Folder 456)
    Discusses Ford Foundation assistance for government-personnel training and legal development in the newly independent countries of Africa below the Sahara
  - International Educational Exchange, Melvin J. Fox (2 copies), 1966 June 27 (Box 36, Folder 457)
  - Education, Universities, and Economic Development, Frank Bowles (2 copies), 1966 January 29 (Box 36, Folder 458)
    From a commencement address at the Trinidad campus of the University of the West Indies
  - Leadership Development Pamphlets - Regional Offices (2 copies) and Field Offices (2 copies), 1969 (Box 36, Folder 459)
  - The Ford Foundation in Pakistan (2 copies), circa 1965 (Box 36, Folder 460)
  - American Professionals Overseas, Irwin T. Sanders (2 copies), 1965 (Box 36, Folder 461)
    Adapted from three papers by Irwin T. Sanders
  - Planning and Participation, Mitchell Sviridoff (2 copies), 1969 January 24 (Box 36, Folder 462)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered before the American Institute of Planners in Washington, D.C.
  - Ford Foundation Faculty Research Fellowships in Business and Economics 1956-68 (2 copies), 1968 October (Box 36, Folder 463)
  - Population Policy and Programs in Southeast Asia: A Discussion of Limiting Factors, Gordon W. Perkin, M.D. (2 copies), 1968 October (Box 36, Folder 464)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered before the "Beyond Nationalism" Seminar of the Press Foundation of Asia, October 14-18, 1968
  - Strategy for Fertility Control, Oscar Harkavy (2 copies), 1966 August 25 (Box 36, Folder 465)
    Paper adapted from Harkavy's commencement address to the Training Program in the Physiology of Reproduction at the Worcester Foundation for Experimental Biology, Shrewbsury, Massachusetts
  - Ford Foundation Strategy for Population Work, Oscar Harkavy, Lyle Saunders, and Anna L. Southam (3 copies), 1968 (Box 36, Folder 466)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Demography, 1968, Volume 5, Number 2, a special issue devoted to "Progress and Problems of Fertility Control Around the World"
  - Language Development: Selected Papers from a Ford Foundation Conference on the State of the Art (2 copies), 1968 October (Box 37, Folder 467)
  - The Newsman's Scope, Ben H. Bagdikian (2 copies), 1968 September (Box 37, Folder 468)
    Details Ford Foundation funding to advance the field of journalism
  - Urban Extension: A Report on Experimental Programs Assisted by the Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1966 October (Box 37, Folder 469)
  - The Importance of Being Different, Julius A. Stratton (2 copies), 1968 October 8 (Box 37, Folder 470)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered on the occasion of the installation of Frederick Seitz as president of the Rockefeller University, New York
  - The Present-Minded Professor, Fred W. Friendly (2 copies), 1968 November 28 (Box 37, Folder 471)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered before the National Council of Teachers of English at Milwaukee, Wisconsin
  - U.S. Domestic and Foreign Policies and World Food Needs, David E. Bell (2 copies), 1968 (Box 37, Folder 472)
    Reprinted from The Land-Grant University and World Food Needs, published by University of Illinois College of Agriculture
  - Q & A On Agriculture, Science, and the Developing World: A Briefing on International Agriculture and Training Centers Supported by the Rockefeller Foundation and the Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1968 October (Box 37, Folder 473)
  - A Worldwide Campus for Management, Marshall A. Robinson (2 copies), 1966 June 6 (Box 37, Folder 474)
    Address given at a meeting of the Association of Canadian Schools of Business at Sherbrooke, Quebec
  - Action for Equal Opportunity, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1966 August 2 (Box 37, Folder 475)
    Excerpts from an address given at the annual banquet of the National Urban League in Philadelphia
  - Pay-As-You-Earn: Ford Foundation Studies in Income Contingent Loans for Higher Education, Summary Report and Recommendations (2 copies), 1972 September (Box 37, Folder 476)
  - Ford Foundation Finances: The Claims of Present and Future, McGeorge Bundy (2 copies), 1971 (Box 37, Folder 477)
    Excerpt from the Ford Foundation Annual Report 1971
  - La Fundación Ford en el Perú, Ford Foundation Program in Peru (2 copies), 1972 (Box 37, Folder 478)
  - Openness - the New Kick in Education, Harold Howe II (2 copies), 1972 February 7 (Box 37, Folder 479)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Adapted from the 1972 Frank Ellsworth Spaulding Lecture on Education at Yale University
  - Point Four in Retrospect, David E. Bell (2 copies), 1971 October 12 (Box 37, Folder 480)
    An address that inaugurated a lecture series honoring President Truman at Avila College in Kansas City, Missouri
  - A Survey of Black American Doctorates, James W. Bryant (2 copies), 1969 (Box 37, Folder 481)
  - The Ford Foundation Charter and Bylaws, 1971 January (Box 37, Folder 482)
  - The Ford Foundation Charter and Bylaws, 1980 September (Box 37, Folder 483)
  - The Ford Foundation Charter and Bylaws (2 copies), 1972 June (Box 37, Folder 484)
  - The Ford Foundation Charter and Bylaws (2 copies), 1975 April (Box 37, Folder 485)
  - The Ford Foundation Charter and Bylaws (2 copies), 1978 June (Box 37, Folder 486)
  - The Search for the Public Interest, Howard R. Dressner (2 copies), 1969 November 12 (Box 37, Folder 487)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Address delivered before the 13th Annual Conference of the National Council on Philanthropy in Houston, Texas
  - Developing Our Wasted Human Resources, Basil J. Whiting (2 copies), 1969 (Box 37, Folder 488)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - address delivered at the Third Annual Summer Manpower Research Institute, Iowa State University, Ames, Iowa, June 2-6, 1969
  - Ford Foundation Grants in Population (2 copies), 1966 October (Box 37, Folder 489)
  - Making Education Relevant, Marvin J. Feldman (2 copies), 1966 April 2 (Box 38, Folder 490)
  - Prospecting in Economics (2 copies), 1966 December (Box 38, Folder 491)
  - Public Policy: Published Annually by the Graduate School of Public Administration, Harvard University, John Montgomery and Arthur Smithies, 1966 (Box 38, Folder 492)
    Volume XV
  - Ford Foundation Program in Public Policy and Social Organization (2 copies), 1976 June (Box 38, Folder 493, Box 112, Folder 1305)
  - "Telelectures," Robert H. Collins (2 copies), 1966 November (Box 38, Folder 494)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Southern Education Report, Vol. 2, No. 4
  - The Institution Building Project, George F. Gant (2 copies), 1966 (Box 38, Folder 495)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint for International Review of Administrative Science, Vol. XXXII, 1966, No. 3.
  - A Perspective on International Development, John F. Hilliard (2 copies), 1967 (Box 38, Folder 496)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint from Universities and Development Assistance Abroad, published by The American Council on Education, Washington, D.C.
  - …and Justice for All (2 copies), 1967 August (Box 38, Folder 497)
  - Expanding the Community of Education, Edward J. Meade, Jr. (2 copies), 1967 April 17 (Box 38, Folder 498)
    Address delivered before the Massachusetts Association of School Superintendents in Bridgewater, Massachusetts
  - From Manpower to Mankind: Some Reflections on the Future of International Education, F. Champion Ward (2 copies), 1967 (Box 38, Folder 499)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Paper prepared for a conference on "Higher Education and International Flow of Manpower: Implications for the Developing World" at the University of Minnesota, April 12-14, 1967
  - A Richer Harvest: A Report on Ford Foundation Grants in Overseas Agriculture (2 copies), 1967 October (Box 38, Folder 500)
  - Taking Advantage of the Disadvantaged, Mario D. Fantini and Gerald Weinstein (2 copies), 1967 November (Box 38, Folder 501)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - from The Record, Teachers College, Columbia University, Volume 69, Number 2
  - IITA - International Institute of Tropical Agriculture, Ibadan, Nigeria (2 copies), 1968 October (Box 38, Folder 502)
    A Joint Project of the Ford Foundation and the Rockefeller Foundation
  - Impact of Family-Planning Programs on the Birth Rate, Oscar Harkavy (2 copies), 1967 April (Box 38, Folder 503)
    A Ford Foundation Reprint - Paper prepared for the Eighth International Conference of the International Planned Parenthood Federation, Santiago, Chile
  - New Options in the Philanthropic Process: A Ford Foundation Statement of Policy (2 copies), 1968 November (Box 38, Folder 504)
  - Current Status of Family Planning Programs in the United States, Gordon W. Perkin, M.D. and David Radel, Population Program, Ford Foundation (2 copies), 1966 October (Box 38, Folder 505)
  - The World Press, Shepard Stone (2 copies), 1962 December 6 (Box 38, Folder 506)
    Excerpts from an addess before the New England Society of Newspaper Editors in Boston, Massachusetts, 1962
  - The Ford Foundation Program in Education 1961 (Box 38, Folder 507)
    Excerpted from the Ford Foundation Annual Report 1961, October 1, 1960-September 30, 1961
  - Faculty Salaries, Hospital Support, Medical Education: A Statement by the Trustees of the Ford Foundation, Special Appropriations (2 copies), 1955 December 8-10 (Box 38, Folder 508)